<?xml version="1.0"?>
<gameList>
	<game>
		<path>./Commander Genius.sh</path>
		<name>Commander Keen</name>
		<desc>Barry Blaze, ordinary schoolkid, by day, Commander Keen, intergalactic superhero, by night. 
In this, the first story, Billy gets stuck on Mars when the evil Vorticons steal his space ship pieces and has to travel around the whole planet looking for them so he can get back and stop the Vorticons from blowing up earth. 
Riveting storyline right? Well... ok, so maybe it wasn't brilliant but to give it some credit, not too many games included real stories linked into the action in those days. Here you were actually on a mission linked to the plot and not just wandering around from level to level like a nerd at a hot party. 
The story of Keen 1, while not mind-blowing is certainly passable and definitely adds a little extra to the whole game.</desc>
		<image>./media/images/Commander Keen 1 - Marooned On Mars.png</image>
		<thumbnail>./media/boxart/Commander Keen 1 - Marooned On Mars.png</thumbnail>
		<video>./media/videos/Commander Keen 1 - Marooned On Mars.mp4</video>
		<rating>0.8</rating>
		<releasedate>19901214T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Ideas From the Deep</developer>
		<publisher>Apogee</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./openomf.sh</path>
		<name>One Must Fall 2097</name>
		<desc>One Must Fall 2097 is a fighting game with a twist. Instead of the usual Street Fighter II trend of games, in this game you play one of 10 characters controlling one of 10 huge robots in a fighting match.According to the game, in the year 2097, the human race is controlled by one company known as W.A.R., which started as a small company providing the Earth government with construction robots. After a while W.A.R. grew further and further and eventually took over Earth Gov.In the year 2097, W.A.R. decided to colonize Ganymede, one of Jupiter's moons. Because of the harsh climate and difficult terrain, they sought for one person, the best of the best, to rule Ganymede for them. They've decided the best way to choose this person is to organize a huge contest, in which the winner will earn a seat in the W.A.R. high counsel and control of Ganymede.You're one of the contestants, and you want to win.</desc>
		<image>./media/images/openomf.png</image>
		<video>./media/videos/openomf.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail>./media/boxart/openomf.png</thumbnail>
		<releasedate />
		<developer>Diversions Entertainment</developer>
		<publisher>Epic MegaGames</publisher>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./SorR.sh</path>
		<name>Streets of Rage Remake</name>
		<desc>Streets of Rage Remake is a remastered version of the MegaDrive classic.
You'll go throughout an immense town fighting against people who try to attack you. There are more than 60 different enemies, you can choose among 16 characters, choose your favourite one and kick asses out there.
It's even better than the original one. More characters, more levels, more actions, more finals,... Amazing.</desc>
		<image>./media/images/sorr.png</image>
		<video>./media/videos/sorr.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail>./media/thumbnails/sorr.png</thumbnail>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Exult-keyring.sh</path>
		<name>Ultima VII Part 1: The Black Gate Forge Of Virtue with keyring</name>
		<desc>Even today Ultima VII is still considered one of the greatest roleplaying games ever made. 
 
The game begins when you, the Avatar, are summoned after receiving a taunting message from a being known as the Guardian. Upon arriving, the Avatar is confronted by the scene of a brutal murder. As you begin to investigate, it becomes clear that all is not as it should be in Britannia. Magic is dying, mages are affected by a strange madness, and despite your previous adventures people have forgotten who you are. Many are now captivated by virtuous and benevolent organization known as The Fellowship, who is perhaps not as they seem.</desc>
		<rating>0.95</rating>
		<releasedate>19920101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Origin Systems</developer>
		<publisher>Electronic Arts</publisher>
		<genre>Role playing games</genre>
		<players>1</players>
		<hash>5B1A2957</hash>
		<image>./media/images/Ultima VII Part 1 - The Black Gate Forge Of Virtue.png</image>
		<thumbnail>./media/boxart/Ultima VII Part 1 - The Black Gate Forge Of Virtue.png</thumbnail>
		<video>./media/videos/Ultima VII Part 1 - The Black Gate Forge Of Virtue.mp4</video>
		<genreid>768</genreid>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./rvgl.sh</path>
		<name>Revolt GL</name>
		<image>./media/images/rvgl.jpg</image>
		<video>./media/videos/rvgl.mp4</video>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Sonic 2.sh</path>
		<name>Sonic The Hedgehog 2</name>
		<desc>Sonic the Hedgehog 2 is a side-scrolling platformer based around speed, and the sequel to Sonic the Hedgehog. Players run through different worlds called "Zones", each with a specific theme. There are two Acts in nearly all of the 10 Zones, and at the end of each Zone's last Act is a machine that Robotnik controls, which you must defeat to progress. Sonic and Tails can collect rings which are scattered throughout all of the levels. When the player collects 100 rings they earn an extra life. The rings also act as protection - if Sonic is hurt when he is carrying rings, they scatter everywhere and he is briefly invincible. If he is hit again when he has no rings, he'll lose a life. If the player reaches a continue point lamppost with 50 or more rings, they'll be able to access the Special Stage. In this stage, you must gather a set amount of rings in a halfpipe-like stage before you reach a checkpoint. Complete all the checkpoints and you'll earn one of the seven Chaos Emeralds. The game also includes the ability to play the game co-op with a friend - at any time, a player can plug in a second controller and take over the AI controlled Tails. Tails has infinite lives and the camera remains focused on Sonic, meaning that Tails will not hinder play. Sonic (and Tails) can now also get speed from a standing start by holding down and repeatedly pressing the jump button for a "Spin Dash". This is useful when stuck near steep slopes or other areas where you need some momentum. The game also features a 2-player versus mode. This mode is a horizontally split-screen race through levels based on three of the zones in the single player game.</desc>
		<image>./media/images/Sonic 2.png</image>
		<video>./media/videos/Sonic 2.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail>./media/boxart/Sonic 2.png</thumbnail>
		<rating>0.85</rating>
		<releasedate>19920101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Sega</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<genre>Action-Platform</genre>
		<players>2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Marathon 2.sh</path>
		<name>Marathon 2</name>
		<video>./media/videos/Marathon 2.mp4</video>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Marathon.sh</path>
		<name>Marathon</name>
		<video>./media/videos/Marathon 1.mp4</video>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Marathon Infinity.sh</path>
		<name>Marathon Infinity</name>
		<video>./media/videos/Marathon Infinity.mp4</video>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Abuse.sh</path>
		<name>Abuse</name>
		<desc>Abuse is a side-scrolling platformer with a lot of shooting. It's a nonlinear game, as the levels often have a few exits that lead to different areas. Your character is a cyborg equipped with various weapons; initially, you only have a weak laser rifle with unlimited ammo, but you can find more powerful guns later on, such as grenade launchers, flamethrowers or lightsabers. You move through a building complex, fighting any enemies you might encounter on the way. The enemies are mostly the mutants, but also the defense systems (such as stationary missile launchers).
While you move with the keyboard, you can aim with your mouse, so you can shoot at any angle no matter what direction you are running. On your way, you'll find elevators, teleporters, cracked walls that can be destroyed and more.
Apart from ammo and health, you can also find upgrades which have a number of beneficial effect - increasing your running speed, for example.</desc>
		<image>./media/images/abuse.png</image>
		<video>./media/videos/abuse.mp4</video>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Blobby Volley 2.sh</path>
		<name>Blobby Volley 2</name>
		<desc>Blobby Volley 2 is a volleyball game in two dimensions with only left, right and up as controls.</desc>
		<image>./media/images/blobbyvolley2.jpg</image>
		<video>./media/videos/blobbyvolley2.mp4</video>
		<rating>0.8</rating>
		<genre>Strategy</genre>
		<players>2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./RAWGL.sh</path>
		<name>Another World - Out of this World</name>
		<desc>A young physics professor named Lester conducts a particle experiment. Suddenly, something goes wrong, a lightning strikes, and in a moment Lester finds himself in a strange alien world. Now he must fight for his life, first with his bare hands, then with a gun he finds. But what gives him courage is that he is not alone. One of the aliens who escapes from the prison together with him helps him on his dangerous quest. Friendship can overcome all the obstacles.
Out of This World combines shooting, platforming, and puzzle-solving elements. The game is divided into stages; some of them are straightforward and can only be accessed one time, while others are connected to each other, constituting a larger environment. Exploration and problem-solving are emphasized. Many levels include challenges not seen in the previous ones. Tasks may involve environmental puzzles, timed sequences, precise jumping, and combat.
Typically, enemies are defeated by using an energy gun found in an early stage. The gun's regular function is shooting energy projectiles. By pressing down and holding the fire button the player can activate an energy shield which protects Lester from regular attacks, allowing him to fire from relative safety until it evaporates. Finally, by holding the fire button even longer the gun creates powerful blasts which can disrupt shields. Most enemies are equipped with similar guns and are able to perform the same actions as Lester. Fighting enemies therefore requires tactical usage of regular attacks, shields, and bombs, as well as learning enemy patterns.
Each level can be accessed by typing a code the player learns after having completed the level. If Lester dies, the level must be restarted. There is no on-screen interface and no in-game dialogue in the game. Vector graphics are used for creating the game's environments and animated cutscenes.</desc>
		<image>./media/images/anotherworld.png</image>
		<video>./media/videos/anotherworld.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail>./media/boxart/anotherworld.png</thumbnail>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./2048.sh</path>
		<name>2048</name>
		<image>./media/images/2048.png</image>
		<video>./media/videos/2048.mp4</video>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Bermuda Syndrome.sh</path>
		<name>Bermuda Syndrome</name>
		<desc>Jack Thompson is a pilot of an American B-17 bomber during World War II. His plane is shot down by German fighters and is about to crash. However, a mysterious portal appears, transporting Jack into an alternate reality. Jack ends up in a jungle and promptly saves a young woman who is attacked by a gigantic dinosaur. It appears that the woman is a princess who was about to be sacrificed for her father. The two decide to travel together, trying to survive in the dangerous jungle and eventually escape.Bermuda Syndrome is a cinematic platformer similar in concept to Flashback. The emphasis of the gameplay is on solving problems and carefully proceeding through screens filled with enemies and hazards. Jumping, fighting, and occasionally using items are required to succeed. At some points it is necessary to interact with the princess in order to solve a puzzle.</desc>
		<image>./media/images/bermuda.png</image>
		<video>./media/videos/bermuda.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail>./media/boxart/bermuda.png</thumbnail>
		<rating>0.7</rating>
		<releasedate>20030530T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Century Interactive</developer>
		<publisher>BMG</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Blake Stone - Planet Strike.sh</path>
		<name>Blake Stone: Planet Strike</name>
		<desc>Blake Stone: Planet Strike continues where Aliens of Gold leaves off.</desc>
		<image>./media/images/bstoneplanetstrike.jpg</image>
		<video>./media/videos/bstoneplanetstrike.mp4</video>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Block Attack.sh</path>
		<name>Block Attack</name>
		<image>./media/images/blockattack-2.3.0-2.png</image>
		<video>./media/videos/Block Attack - Rise of the Blocks.mp4</video>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Blood.sh</path>
		<name>Blood</name>
		<desc>Caleb was once a feared gunslinger, until he met a woman who was involved with a mysterious cult known as Cabal. Caleb, too, is sucked in, and soon becomes one of the Chosen - the most favored worshippers of the evil god Tchernobog. But one day, Tchernobog inexplicably kills the four Chosen, including Caleb. Mysteriously resurrected years later, Caleb is out to get revenge, and learn why his lord cast him down so abruptly.
Blood is a first-person shooter with horror elements, which uses the Build engine. Similarly to Duke Nukem 3D, the environment is interactive: many objects can be physically moved or affected in other ways. Destruction of landscapes is possible (although only in specific spots), with bullet holes being left by misplaced shots. The Build engine version is 2.5D, so there are rooms above rooms and puzzles which are based on this.</desc>
		<emulator>retroarch32</emulator>
		<image>./media/images/Blood.png</image>
		<video>./media/videos/Blood.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail>./media/boxart/Blood.png</thumbnail>
		<rating>0.85</rating>
		<releasedate>19970531T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Monolith Productions, Inc.</developer>
		<publisher>GT Interactive</publisher>
		<genre>Shooter / 1st person-Shooter</genre>
		<players>40</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Blues Brothers.sh</path>
		<name>Blues Brothers, The</name>
		<desc>The Blues Brothers are on the run from the law. Take control of either bulky Jake or nippy Elwood in this five-level platform game. You must cross a prison, a river and the big city to reach freedom. You also must find your missing records and collect these. Everything and everyone is against you, but you can pick up and throw warehouse crates to defeat your opponents.</desc>
		<image>./media/images/bb.png</image>
		<video>./media/videos/bb.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail>./media/boxart/bb.png</thumbnail>
		<developer>Titus</developer>
		<publisher>Titus</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Cannonball.sh</path>
		<name>Out Run</name>
		<desc>Out Run is a ground-breaking racing game in which the player drives a red Ferrari Testarossa through a number of colourful European locations, trying to reach each end-of-level checkpoint before the tight time limit expires. 
Each of the game's stages is packed with civilian traffic that must be carefully avoided, as players try to negotiate the game's twisting, hilly roads.  
At the end of every stage players are presented with a fork in the road, allowing them to chose which route they wish to take next. This was not the first time this feature had appeared (Tatsumi's 1983 racer, TX-1, was the first to introduce forked roads). 
As well as being able to choose routes, players could also - via the game's "in-car radio" - choose one of three different catchy tunes to listen to while driving. The songs are 'Magical Sound Shower', 'Passing Breeze' and 'Splash Wave'.</desc>
		<image>./media/images/outrun.png</image>
		<video>./media/videos/outrun.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail>./media/boxart/outrun.png</thumbnail>
		<rating>0.9</rating>
		<releasedate>19860101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Sega</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<genre>Race 3rd Pers. view-Race, Driving</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./C-Dogs.sh</path>
		<name>C-Dogs</name>
		<desc>C-Dogs, the sequel to Cyberdogs, is a shoot 'em up computer game where players work cooperatively during missions, and against each other in "dogfight" deathmatch mode.</desc>
		<image>./media/images/cdogs.png</image>
		<video>./media/videos/cdogs.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail>./media/boxart/cdogs.png</thumbnail>
		<releasedate />
		<developer>Diversions Entertainment</developer>
		<publisher>Epic MegaGames</publisher>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Iconoclasts.sh</path>
		<name>Iconoclasts</name>
		<image>./media/images/iconoclast.png</image>
		<video>./media/videos/iconoclast.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail>./media/boxart/iconoclast-title.png</thumbnail>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Return to Castle Wolfenstein.sh</path>
		<name>Return to Castle Wolfenstein</name>
		<desc>Coming a full 20 years after the original Castle Wolfenstein and nearly a decade after the first groundbreaking 3D sequel, Return to Castle Wolfenstein updates a video gaming landmark for the next generation of players. In this release, Nazi-bane B.J. Blazkowicz makes his return to a Castle Wolfenstein that is rendered in full 3D with state-of-the-art graphical effects, built on a special version of the Quake III Arena engine.
As in earlier editions in the series, this first-person shooter is set during World War II and takes place deep in the heart of a remote castle that serves as a Nazi stronghold. In the role of B.J., the player becomes involved in a violent adventure of deadly warfare and forbidden occult practices. Utilizing many of the technological advances developed since the release of earlier Wolfenstein games, this sequel is designed to create environments that are as engagingly interactive as possible.</desc>
		<image>./media/images/rtcw.png</image>
		<video>./media/videos/rtcw.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail>./media/boxart/rtcw.png</thumbnail>
		<rating>0.8</rating>
		<releasedate>20030530T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Activision</developer>
		<publisher>id Software</publisher>
		<genre>Shooter / 1st person-Shooter</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Rocks n Diamonds.sh</path>
		<name>Rocks n Diamonds</name>
		<image>./media/images/rocksanddiamonds.png</image>
		<video>./media/videos/rocksanddiamonds.mp4</video>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Rick Dangerous.sh</path>
		<name>Rick Dangerous</name>
		<desc>You play Rick Dangerous, an Indiana Jones type who's on a quest to find the lost Coolu Amazon tribe.  However, his plane crashes in the middle of a bunch of crazed Coolus. Hopefully he's up to the challenge of escaping. If he is, he will find himself in the pyramid of Egypt with no easy way past leaders and their minions, and then engulfed in a web of traps in a Nazi base.Rick Dangerous is a platform game across over 100 screens, in which Rick has his gun in one hand, and dynamite sticks in another. You must take a methodical approach to clearing each screen, as there are traps in place which will need memorizing and preempting where possible. Use the dynamite wisely, for enemies you can't get into the purely-horizontal range of your gun.</desc>
		<image>./media/images/Rick Dangerous.png</image>
		<video>./media/videos/Rick Dangerous.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail>./media/boxart/Rick Dangerous.png</thumbnail>
		<rating>0.9</rating>
		<releasedate>19890101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Core Design</developer>
		<publisher>Microplay Software</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
		<players>1</players>
		<genreid>257</genreid>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./ROTT.sh</path>
		<name>Rise of the Triad</name>
		<desc>A madman with power to kill millions has been discovered, and HUNT (High-risk United Nations Taskforce) has been dispatched to discover his plans. Your team was infiltrating his island stronghold when everything went to hell. The infiltration boat exploded and fire came from all directions. The only way out is in, into the the fortress, but to stay out here would be certain death. So in you go, guns blazing...Rise of the Triad, a first-person shooter, is the successor of Wolfenstein 3D, with a somewhat improved 3D engine. Everything is still composed from blocks, but multiple vertical levels have been added; there are stairs made of platforms floating in air, and jump pads which launch you (and the enemies) high up so that you can walk over tall barriers in your way. The game offers a lot of weapons. You begin with a pistol, but later you can find an extra pistol for John Woo-style shooting, and a MP40 rifle. All these weapons have unlimited ammo. You can also find more potent weapons - from classic rocket launcher, to quite wacky contraptions such as a ''drunk missile'' launcher or the ''Excalibat'', a powerful baseball bat. However, you can carry only one such a strong weapon at a time, and they have limited ammo. Enemies are mostly humans equipped with various weapons. Their attacks can be quite varied; some of them can steal your weapons (though you can retrieve them after killing them), other shoot nets at you that trap you (you have to wriggle out, unless you found a knife, which will allow you to cut your way out). Apart from enemies, you'll be endangered by fireball launchers, rolling boulders and crushing walls. There's a lot of power-ups you can pick up. They all have various wacky effects: for example, ''God Mode'' makes you immortal and allows you to toss homing, insta-death missiles; ''Dog Mode'' turns you into a... dog, which can fit into small spaces (and is inexplicably invulnerable to weapons); ''Shrooms Mode'' makes everything shine with bright colours, as if you were on drugs; ''Elasto Mode'' makes you very prone to bouncing off walls when you run into them. ROTT also offers a lot of multi-player game modes; there's the standard deathmatch and ''Capture the Triad'', but there are also more varied modes - e.g. in ''Collector'' the players have no weapons, instead trying to collect as many ''triads'' as possible; in ''Deluder'', the players earn points by destroying ''eluders'' which move around the level.</desc>
		<image>./media/images/rott.png</image>
		<video>./media/videos/rott.mp4</video>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Shadow Warrior.sh</path>
		<name>Shadow Warrior</name>
		<desc>Lo Wang has been working as a Shadow Warrior (a bodyguard and mercenary of sorts) for the powerful Zilla Corporation for years. But when he discovered the evil Zilla's plan to summon monsters from other dimensions and conquer the world, he left in disgust. Realizing that Lo Wang might jeopardize his plans, Zilla sends his assassins after him.Shadow Warrior is a first-person shooter similar in style and gameplay to Duke Nukem 3D. The game set in a generic ''Asialand'', which looks like China and Japan conflated together. It features deliberately immature and politically incorrect humor, as well as a protagonist who delivers regular one-liners, commenting upon the situation at hand. Much of the humor is derived from over-the-top, stereotypical portrayals of Asian culture (e.g. scantily clad young women drawn in Japanese anime style). The player has to complete several levels, fighting enemies and occasionally solving puzzles on the way. Though the game primarily focuses on exploration and combat, puzzle-solving plays a larger role than in most other contemporary shooters. There are also a few sequences that allow the player to drive vehicles, some of which have mounted weapons. Like Duke Nukem 3D, the game's environments are interactive, allowing the player to manipulate or destroy scenery and many objects, often revealing secret areas. On a technical side, the game introduces climbable ladders, true room-over-room situations, and voxels (instead of sprites) for weapons and inventory items.Enemies include evil ninjas with various weapons, ''coolies'' which carry a crate of dynamite and blow themselves up when near the player character, female assassins with crossbows, and many more. To combat them, Lo Wang can use a variety of weapons and items. Weapons include: Lo Wang's fists, a katana, shuriken, a riot gun, an Uzi (two of which can be equipped and used at a time), a rocket launcher firing heat-seeking or nuclear missile, a grenade launcher, sticky bombs, a railgun, and even some enemy body parts. Many of these weapons have a secondary firing mode. Lo Wang can also find and use gadgets such as caltrops to leave in the enemies' way, or gas bombs to choke foes who happen to be near it.</desc>
		<image>./media/images/Shadow Warrior.png</image>
		<video>./media/videos/Shadow Warrior.mp4</video>
		<rating>0.8</rating>
		<releasedate>19970101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>3D Realms</developer>
		<publisher>GT Interactive</publisher>
		<genre>Shooter-Action-Shooter / 1st person</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Cave Story.sh</path>
		<name>Cave Story</name>
		<desc>Cave Story takes you into a rare world where a curious race of innocent, rabbit-like creatures called Mimiga run free. You wake up in a dark cave with no memory of who you are, where you came from or why you're in such a place. Uncovering Mimiga Village, you discover that the once-carefree Mimiga are in danger at the hands of a maniacal scientist. Their only hope rests squarely on the shoulders of a quiet, amnesiac boy who can't remember his own name. Take control, learn the origins of this world's power, stop the delusional villain and save the Mimiga.</desc>
		<image>./media/images/Cave Story.png</image>
		<video>./media/videos/Cave Story.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail>./media/boxart/Cave Story.png</thumbnail>
		<rating>0.9</rating>
		<releasedate>20041220T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Pixel Studios</developer>
		<publisher>Pixel Studios</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Blake Stone - Aliens of Gold.sh</path>
		<name>Blake Stone: Aliens of Gold</name>
		<desc>Blake Stone: Aliens of Gold or Blake Stone 3D is a first-person shooter for DOS created by JAM Productions and published by Apogee Software in 1993. It plays similarly to Castle Wolfenstein 3D</desc>
		<image>./media/images/bstoneaog.jpg</image>
		<video>./media/videos/bstoneaog.mp4</video>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Cave Story-evo.sh</path>
		<name>Cave Story Evo</name>
		<desc>Cave Story takes you into a rare world where a curious race of innocent, rabbit-like creatures called Mimiga run free. You wake up in a dark cave with no memory of who you are, where you came from or why you're in such a place. Uncovering Mimiga Village, you discover that the once-carefree Mimiga are in danger at the hands of a maniacal scientist. Their only hope rests squarely on the shoulders of a quiet, amnesiac boy who can't remember his own name. Take control, learn the origins of this world's power, stop the delusional villain and save the Mimiga.</desc>
		<image>./media/images/Cave Story.png</image>
		<video>./media/videos/Cave Story.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail>./media/boxart/Cave Story.png</thumbnail>
		<rating>0.9</rating>
		<releasedate>20041220T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Pixel Studios</developer>
		<publisher>Pixel Studios</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Invaders.sh</path>
		<name>Space Invaders</name>
		<desc>si78c is a memory accurate reimplementation of the 1978 arcade game Space Invaders in C. It requires the original arcade ROM to function to load various sprites and other data, but does not use the original game code. It is not an emulation, but rather a restoration.</desc>
		<image>./media/images/invaders.png</image>
		<video>./media/videos/invaders.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail>./media/boxart/invaders.png</thumbnail>
		<rating>0.9</rating>
		<releasedate>19780101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Taito</developer>
		<publisher>Taito</publisher>
		<genre>Shooter-Shooter / Space Invaders Like</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./OpenJazz.sh</path>
		<name>Jazz Jackrabbit</name>
		<desc>Jazz Jackrabbit is a series of platform video games featuring the eponymous character, Jazz Jackrabbit, a green anthropomorphic hare, who fights with his nemesis, Devan Shell, in a science fiction parody of the fable, The Tortoise and the Hare. Created by Arjan Brussee and Cliff Bleszinski and developed by Epic Games, the series debuted on MS-DOS in 1994 with Jazz Jackrabbit.</desc>
		<image>./media/images/Jazz Jackrabbit.png</image>
		<video>./media/videos/Jazz Jackrabbit.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail>./media/boxart/Jazz Jackrabbit.png</thumbnail>
		<releasedate>19940801T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Epic MegaGames</developer>
		<publisher>Epic MegaGames</publisher>
		<genre>Platform-Plateform / Shooter Scrolling</genre>
 	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Exhumed.sh</path>
		<name>Exhumed / Power Slave</name>
		<desc>In this First person shooter, you're an armed forces specialist sent to investigate strange happenings at the ancient Egyptian city of Karnak. Soon you learn that alien invaders with a penchant for mummifying humans alive have taken over the place. You have to fight your way through increasingly difficult levels with an unbelievable cast in order to finish it.</desc>
		<image>./media/images/Power Slave.png</image>
		<video>./media/videos/Power Slave.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail>./media/boxart/Power Slave.png</thumbnail>
		<rating>0.65</rating>
		<releasedate>19960101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Lobotomy Software, Inc.</developer>
		<publisher>Playmates Interactive</publisher>
		<genre>Shooter / 1st person-Shooter</genre>
 	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Duke Nukem 3D.sh</path>
		<name>Duke Nukem 3D</name>
		<desc>Duke Nukem, the politically incorrect action hero and ultimate alien ass kicker, defends Earth and its babes from alien invasion in Duke Nukem 3D. This is the award winning game that helped define the FPS genre, introducing unparalleled interactivity, and a main character that spoke. Take the fight to the aliens across 39 levels featuring Hollywood, Los Angeles, a moon base, and alien spacecraft. Innovative items like the Jetpack, HoloDuke, Shrink Ray, or Pipe Bombs allow you to fight the aliens in any style you want. Defeat the aliens, so Duke can get back to some R&amp;R with a stogie, a warm belly, and a bottle of Jack.</desc>
		<image>./media/images/Duke Nukem 3D.png</image>
		<video>./media/videos/Duke Nukem 3D.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail>./media/boxart/Duke Nukem 3D.png</thumbnail>
		<rating>0.85</rating>
		<releasedate>19960129T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>3D Realms</developer>
		<publisher>GT Interactive</publisher>
		<genre>Shooter / 1st person-Shooter</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./F2bgl.sh</path>
		<name>Fade to Black</name>
		<desc>F2bgl is a rewrite of the engine used in the game Fade To Black.</desc>
		<image>./media/images/f2bgl.png</image>
		<video>./media/videos/f2bgl.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail>./media/boxart/f2bgl-thumb.png</thumbnail>
		<rating>0.8</rating>
		<developer>Delphine Software</developer>
		<publisher>Electronic Arts</publisher>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Hurrican.sh</path>
		<name>Hurrican</name>
		<desc>Hurrican is a freeware jump and shoot game based on the Turrican game series. Blast your way through nine action-packed levels filled with different enemies and powerups.</desc>
		<image>./media/images/hurrican.png</image>
		<video>./media/videos/hurrican.mp4</video>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Freedom Planet.sh</path>
		<name>Freedom Planet</name>
		<desc>The planet Avalice has long known a tenuous peace thanks to the Kingdom Stone: an orb of unknown origin that outputs enough free energy to power every device in the world, seemingly without limit.
The Kingdom Stone is beginning to weaken, however, and the planet's three ruling houses are poised to engage in all-out war over control of this most precious resource. Add to that a coup d'etat within one of these houses – instigated by an invading alien army – and Avalice's future is looking grim.</desc>
		<image>./media/images/Freedom_Planet.jpg</image>
		<video>./media/videos/Freedom_Planet-video.mp4</video>
		<developer>Galaxy Trail</developer>
		<publisher>Marvelous Entertainment Inc.</publisher>
		<genre>Platform / Adventure</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Exult-nokeyring.sh</path>
		<name>Ultima VII Part 1: The Black Gate Forge Of Virtue no keyring yet</name>
		<desc>Even today Ultima VII is still considered one of the greatest roleplaying games ever made. The game begins when you, the Avatar, are summoned after receiving a taunting message from a being known as the Guardian. Upon arriving, the Avatar is confronted by the scene of a brutal murder. As you begin to investigate, it becomes clear that all is not as it should be in Britannia. Magic is dying, mages are affected by a strange madness, and despite your previous adventures people have forgotten who you are. Many are now captivated by virtuous and benevolent organization known as The Fellowship, who is perhaps not as they seem.</desc>
		<image>./media/images/Ultima VII Part 1 - The Black Gate Forge Of Virtue.png</image>
		<video>./media/videos/Ultima VII Part 1 - The Black Gate Forge Of Virtue.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail>./media/boxart/Ultima VII Part 1 - The Black Gate Forge Of Virtue.png</thumbnail>
		<rating>0.95</rating>
		<releasedate>19920101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Origin Systems</developer>
		<publisher>Electronic Arts</publisher>
		<genre>Role playing games</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./NAM.sh</path>
		<name>NAM</name>
		<desc>The year is 1966, shortly after USA deployed its troops to participate in the Vietnam War. Alan ''The Bear'' Westmoreland, a Marine Corps sergeant, is sent behind the enemy lines. He is known for his high endurance, achieved by ingesting various stimulants. As long as these drugs keep him going, the Bear isn't afraid of danger, and is used by his superiors for missions with overwhelming odds. The raid turns into total warfare; with only a small team at his side, the Sergeant will have to do everything he is capable of in order to survive.NAM is a military-themed first-person shooter that uses the Build engine. The protagonist has to fight his way through the jungle, with various weapons such as M16, M60, M79, LAW, and others. The missions range from urban gun battles to sneaking in the thick jungles and man-made tunnels under the ground. The battlefields are frequented by air strikes, anti-personnel mines (which the player can spot with a mine detector), fire fights, ambushes, snipers and tanks. Fellow soldiers will aid Alan in battle, though for the most part he'll have to depend on himself.A multiplayer battle is included, featuring 19 multiplayer levels with different game modes like Gruntmatch, Capture-the-flag and Fireteam, where each player is allowed to select a soldier type and is sent on different missions.</desc>
		<image>./media/images/NAM.png</image>
		<video>./media/videos/NAM.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail>./media/boxart/NAM.png</thumbnail>
		<developer>TNT Team</developer>
		<publisher>GT Interactive</publisher>
		<genre>Shooter / 1st person-Shooter</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Openclaw.sh</path>
		<name>Openclaw</name>
		<image>./media/images/openclaw.png</image>
		<video>./media/videos/openclaw.mp4</video>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./REminiscence.sh</path>
		<name>Flashback: The Quest for Identity</name>
		<desc>The year is 2142. The player takes control of Conrad B. Hart, a man who has lost his memory. After barely escaping from hostile aliens, Conrad's bike crashes on an unknown planet. Conrad finds himself in the jungle, and from that moment on his quest for survival and his lost identity begins.Flashback: The Quest for Identity incorporates elements of platforming, shooting, and problem-solving. The game can be described as a ''cinematic platformer'' (commonly referred to as Prince of Persia-style), following a design philosophy that was also manifested in Delphine Software's previous work, Another World. Compared to that game, Flashback focuses more on platforming and exploration of large levels.While a large bulk of the gameplay is dedicated to running, jumping, and shooting enemies, there is also a considerable exploration element in the game, as well as some puzzle-solving. The player navigates Conrad through platform structures, performing various moves. It is possible to simply jump or do a longer run-and-jump, run, climb, hang off ledges, and pick up objects lying on the ground. To defend himself, Conrad can shoot enemies with his gun and also use various objects (such as stones) to harm or distract them. Crouching and rolling are possible (and often essential) moves that can be executed during combat. The gun has unlimited ammunition; however, shields that Conrad uses to protect himself from attacks are depleted when he is hit, and can be recharged at special stations. Though most environments in the game are hostile, there are a few locations that are devoid of enemies. The player is usually required to talk to characters, gather information and compete tasks in an adventure-like fashion in these areas.</desc>
		<image>./media/images/fb.png</image>
		<video>./media/videos/fb.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail>./media/boxart/fb.png</thumbnail>
		<developer>Delphine Software</developer>
		<publisher>SSI Strategic Simulations Inc</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./RigelEngine.sh</path>
		<name>Duke Nukem 2</name>
		<desc>This project is a re-implementation of the game Duke Nukem II, originally released by Apogee Software in 1993 for MS-DOS.
In the "near future" year 1998, the evil Rigelatins plan to enslave Earth, and they kidnap Duke Nukem (who was performing in an interview about his new autobiography, "Why I'm So Great"), to use his brain to plot the attack for their forces. Duke must break free in order to save the world, once again.</desc>
		<image>./media/images/dukenukem2.png</image>
		<video>./media/videos/dukenukem2.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail>./media/boxart/dukenukem2.png</thumbnail>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Openomf.sh</path>
		<name>Openomf</name>
		<image>./media/images/openomf.png</image>
		<video>./media/videos/openomf.mp4</video>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Maldita Castilla.sh</path>
		<name>Maldita Castilla</name>
		<desc>Guide the valiant Don Ramiro through the cursed lands of Tolomera and fight demons and undead creatures for God and Castilla!</desc>
		<image>./media/images/maldita_castilla_04.png</image>
		<video>./media/videos/Maldita_Castilla-video.mp4</video>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Duke Nukem 3D Atomic.sh</path>
		<name>Duke Nukem 3D Atomic</name>
		<desc>Duke Nukem, the politically incorrect action hero and ultimate alien ass kicker, defends Earth and its babes from alien invasion in Duke Nukem 3D. This is the award winning game that helped define the FPS genre, introducing unparalleled interactivity, and a main character that spoke. Take the fight to the aliens across 39 levels featuring Hollywood, Los Angeles, a moon base, and alien spacecraft. Innovative items like the Jetpack, HoloDuke, Shrink Ray, or Pipe Bombs allow you to fight the aliens in any style you want. Defeat the aliens, so Duke can get back to some R&amp;R with a stogie, a warm belly, and a bottle of Jack.</desc>
		<image>./media/images/Duke Nukem 3D Atomic.png</image>
		<video>./media/videos/Duke Nukem 3D Atomic.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail>./media/boxart/Duke Nukem 3D Atomic.png</thumbnail>
		<rating>0.85</rating>
		<releasedate>19960129T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>3D Realms</developer>
		<publisher>GT Interactive</publisher>
		<genre>Shooter / 1st person-Shooter</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./nKaruga.sh</path>
		<name>nKaruga</name>
		<image>./media/images/nkaruga.jpg</image>
		<video>./media/videos/nkaruga.mp4</video>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Devilutionx.sh</path>
		<name>Diablo</name>
		<desc>Set in the fictional Kingdom of Khanduras, located in the world of Sanctuary, Diablo has the player take control of a lone hero battling to rid the world of Diablo, the Lord of Terror. Beneath the town of Tristram, the player journeys through sixteen dungeon levels, ultimately entering Hell itself in order to face Diablo.</desc>
		<image>./media/images/Diablo (USA) (En,Fr,De,Sv).png</image>
		<video>./media/videos/Diablo (USA) (En,Fr,De,Sv).mp4</video>
		<rating>0.65</rating>
		<releasedate>19980302T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Blizzard</developer>
		<publisher>Electronic Arts</publisher>
		<genre>Role playing games</genre>
		<players>2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Heart of Darkness.sh</path>
		<name>Heart of Darkness</name>
		<desc>The eternally delayed Heart of Darkness has finally made its way to the PlayStation gaming console! One day, as Andy was in the park with his dog Whiskey, strange things started to happen. Almost in an instant, a vortex to some undiscovered realm opened up and sucked the poor doggie in. Determined to get his pooch back, Andy hopped in a homemade flying contraption and set off on a journey; where he was going, he did not know. 
 On his way to this unknown world, Andy was met with some resistance and crash-landed into a wall of pure granite. Upon meeting up with a creepy monster, it was easy to see things were not kosher; this Land of Darkness has been overrun by horrific shadow monsters working in service of the Master of Darkness. It is the player's objective to ultimately destroy this evil nemesis, save Whiskey, and return home with both lives in tact.</desc>
		<emulator>retroarch32</emulator>
		<image>./media/images/Heart of Darkness (USA).png</image>
		<video>./media/videos/Heart of Darkness (USA).mp4</video>
		<rating>0.75</rating>
		<releasedate>19980731T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Amazing Studio</developer>
		<publisher>Ocean</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Mr. Boom.sh</path>
		<name>Mr. Boom</name>
		<desc>Bomberman clone. Gameplay is exactly the same and even the graphic style seems very similar to Bomberman.</desc>
		<image>./media/images/Mr. Boom-image.png</image>
		<video>./media/videos/Mr. Boom-video.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail>./media/boxart/Mr. Boom-thumb.png</thumbnail>
		<rating>0.8</rating>
		<releasedate>19990101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Remdy Software</developer>
		<publisher>Remdy Software</publisher>
		<genre>Strategy</genre>
		<players>8</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./OpenTyrian.sh</path>
		<name>Tyrian</name>
		<desc>Tyrian is a shoot 'em up with a complex plot. You play the role of Trent Hawkings, this galaxy's ace solo fighter-pilot, whose luck forces him to save the galaxy, one time after another. Again and again, Trent must fight off MicroSol, a company with the evil intent of taking over the galaxy. Through your struggles, you will find yourself again and again betrayed by friends and allies, your parents will be killed and you will have to return to points you've already been to (with variations on the levels) in order to remove further threats to the galaxy and to yourself, all for the ultimate goal of overthrowing MicroSol.Tyrian also has two player arcade mode and supports network/modem/serial play. It features a multi-layered ship upgrade engine, in which you can change hulls, decide upon and upgrade your front and rear weapons, buy better shields and generators and even add ship ''sidekicks''. Tyrian's complete arsenal amound to over a dozen type of ships and over 100 weapon types.</desc>
		<image>./media/images/Tyrian.png</image>
		<video>./media/videos/Tyrian.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail>./media/boxart/Tyrian.png</thumbnail>
		<releasedate />
		<developer>Eclipse Software</developer>
		<publisher>Epic MegaGames</publisher>
		<genre>Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Dinothawr.sh</path>
		<name>Dinothawr</name>
		<desc>Dinothawr is a block pushing puzzle game on slippery surfaces. Our hero is a dinosaur whose friends are trapped in ice. Through puzzles it is your task to free the dinos from their ice prison.</desc>
		<image>./media/images/Dinothawr-image.png</image>
		<video>./media/videos/Dinothawr-video.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail>./media/boxart/Dinothawr-thumb.png</thumbnail>
		<rating>0.6</rating>
		<releasedate>20130901T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Agnes Heyer &amp; Hans-Kristian Arntzen</developer>
		<publisher>Libretro</publisher>
		<genre>Puzzle-Game</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Fheroes2.sh</path>
		<name>Heroes of Might and Magic II</name>
		<desc>Heroes of Might and Magic II is a fantasy role-playing game which takes place in the land of Enroth, a place of magic. There are a multitude of creature types, from griffins to rocs, golems to pikemen, unicorns to hydras, and four different dragons. Each castle type has six different creatures, from the weak to the strong. There are six castle types, each corresponding to a hero class: Knight, Sorceress, Wizard (Good side), Barbarian, Necromancer and Warlock (Evil side). There are also six different types of neutral creatures you can recruit in special structures scattered about the maps.</desc>
		<image>./media/images/heroes_of_might_and_magic_ii.png</image>
		<video>./media/videos/heroes_of_might_and_magic_ii.mp4</video>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Hydra Castle Labyrinth.sh</path>
		<name>Hydra Castle Labyrinth</name>
		<desc>Hydra Castle Labyrinth, originally Meikyuujou Hydra, is a freeware Indie platformer developed by E. Hashimoto, a.k.a. Buster, and released on his website. The original game was entirely in Japanese, but saw a translation patch months after its original creation.
The game hearkens back to early "Metroidvania" games like Knightmare II: The Maze of Galious and Legacy of the Wizard: the player explores an immense maze-like dungeon, collecting tools and keys that allow them to proceed deeper. Certain areas are cordoned off from the main dungeon area, and each presents a more linear zone with a boss at the end. The player can find new equipment to make themselves stronger as well.</desc>
		<image>./media/images/hcl.jpg</image>
		<video>./media/videos/Hydra_Castle_Labyrinth-video.mp4</video>
		<rating>0.8</rating>
		<releasedate>20120124T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>E. Hashimoto.</developer>
		<genre>Platform / Adventure</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Redneck Rampage.sh</path>
		<name>Redneck Rampage</name>
		<desc>Redneck Rampage is a pseudo-3D first person shooter much like Duke Nukem 3D, with 2D sprites for enemies and other objects. In fact, it uses the same Build engine as Duke Nukem 3D.Redneck Rampage also has a singularly unique setting... instead of taking place in an alien installation or secret government facility, the game is set in the backwater small town of Hickston, Arkansas. It seems that a bunch of tabloid leather-fetish cyborg aliens have abducted the town's stereotypical redneck inhabitants and cloned them. The aliens have also abducted Bessie, the prize pig of brothers Leonard and Bubba. As Leonard you'll have to fight the local yokel clones as well as the aliens throughout Hickston to rescue your pig. The 'Redneck' theme is used very heavily. Levels range from trailer parks to chicken processing plants, and the arsenal of odd weapons include a gun that shoots circular saws, a TNT crossbow, and even a machine gun bra. Also, instead of armor and health kits, you restore health and become tougher by drinking whisky and eating pork rinds. But if you drink too much you go into ''drunk mode'' with blurred vision and stumbling movement.</desc>
		<image>./media/images/Redneck_rampage.png</image>
		<video>./media/videos/Redneck_rampage.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail>./media/boxart/Redneck_rampage.png</thumbnail>
		<developer>Xatrix</developer>
		<publisher>Interplay</publisher>
		<genre>Shooter / 1st person-Shooter</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Redneck Rampage Rides Again.sh</path>
		<name>Redneck Rampage Rides Again</name>
		<desc>This stand-alone sequel to Redneck Rampage finds Leonard and Bubba shooting their way back to Hickston after crash-landing the UFO at the end of the first game.  Using the same engine and most of the same graphics as the original, RRRA adds vehicles, some new weapons (including a sling blade), new alien clones (a Dennis Hopper-ish biker and an evil cheerleader), and fourteen levels of ass-whuppin'.</desc>
		<image>./media/images/Redneck_Rampage_Rides_Again.png</image>
		<video>./media/videos/Redneck_Rampage_Rides_Again.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail>./media/boxart/Redneck_Rampage_Rides_Again.png</thumbnail>
		<developer>Xatrix</developer>
		<publisher>Interplay</publisher>
		<genre>Shooter / 1st person-Shooter</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Quake 2.sh</path>
		<name>Quake II</name>
		<desc>A sequel in name only, this follow up to idâ€™s 1996 Quake, is a first-person shooter revolving around the Earth-Strogg war. The Strogg alien race threatens the Earth, but Earth has launched a counter-offensive, Operation Alien Overlord. Overlord takes the battle to the Strogg homeworld with the ultimate objective of securing their capital city and killing their ruler.
As a FPS, Quake II contains a variety of weapons including the fall back Blaster, the Railgun, and the secret BFG10K. Health, armor, and ammunition pick-ups can be found during levels, as can the classic Quakeâ€™s Quad Damage power-up. Game play involves mowing down alien opponents as the player progresses through levels, completing in-game objectives. Quake II also comes with multiplayer support for Deathmatches.</desc>
		<image>./media/images/Quake II (USA).png</image>
		<video>./media/videos/Quake II (USA).mp4</video>
		<thumbnail>./media/boxart/Quake II (USA).png</thumbnail>
		<rating>0.6</rating>
		<releasedate>19990930T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Activision</developer>
		<publisher>id Software</publisher>
		<genre>Shooter / 1st person-Shooter</genre>
		<players>2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Prehistorik 2.sh</path>
		<name>Prehistorik 2</name>
		<desc>Prehistorik 2 takes up the story of its predecessor, for another caveman-era platform game.
The hero must use his club to crush animal enemies, many of which then release bonus items to collect. He no longer needs to feed his clan, so there is no required minimum food target, unlike the original game. Other bonus items are located around the levels, while yet more can be found by using your club creatively and adventurously.
Passwords for every level can be found written in various places and they are different on every computer. You also encounter bosses after every few levels. In addition, the game includes hidden locations, multiple level exits and even hidden levels.</desc>
		<image>./media/images/pre2.png</image>
		<video>./media/videos/pre2.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail>./media/boxart/pre2.png</thumbnail>
		<developer>Titus</developer>
		<publisher>Titus</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Shovel Knight.sh</path>
		<name>Shovel Knight</name>
		<image>./media/images/Shovel Knight-image.png</image>
		<video>./media/videos/shovelknight.mp4</video>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./SDLPoP.sh</path>
		<name>Prince Of Persia</name>
		<desc>Prince of Persia was originally released in 1989 for the Apple II by Jordan Mechner. Mechner used film of his younger brother David running, jumping, and performing many of the Prince's actions. Mechner then rotoscoped the film to create the animations that give the Prince his fluid movement. 
Part of the game's appeal was its then unique focus on environmental puzzle-solving, as well as its one-on-one sword duels. Mechner has stated that the game was inspired by the first ten minutes of Raiders of the Lost Ark, for the character's acrobatics in a dangerous environment. 
Prince of Persia has since been ported to a number of different platforms, including the Amiga, Apple Macintosh, DOS, NES, Game Boy, Sega Genesis, Game Gear, SNES, Sharp X68000, Atari ST, and SAM Coupé. 
The music was written by Jordan Mechner's father, Francis Mechner.</desc>
		<image>./media/images/prince of persia.png</image>
		<video>./media/videos/prince of persia.mp4</video>
		<rating>0.6</rating>
		<releasedate>19891003T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Broderbund Software</developer>
		<publisher>Broderbund Software</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
		<players>1</players>
		<playcount>3</playcount>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./World War II GI.sh</path>
		<name>World War II GI</name>
		<desc>World War II GI is a first-person shooter that takes players back to D-Day and the Normandy invasion. The player takes control of a G.I. (''galvanized iron'', referring to a soldier in the US military), sent in to wipe out scores of Wehrmacht and SS soldiers. Missions take the player through the D-Day beach landings, assaults on equipment depots, and other set pieces. This game is based on the Build engine, with 3D environments and 2D character sprites. It shares many gameplay elements with NAM, created by the same developers.</desc>
		<image>./media/images/World_War_II_GI.png</image>
		<video>./media/videos/World_War_II_GI.mp4</video>
		<releasedate />
		<developer>TNT Team</developer>
		<publisher>GT Interactive</publisher>
		<genre>Shooter / 1st person-Shooter</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Quake.sh</path>
		<name>Quake</name>
		<desc>In Quake, the player takes the role of the protagonist known as Ranger who was sent into a portal in order to stop an enemy code-named "Quake". The government had been experimenting with teleportation technology and developed a working prototype called a "Slipgate"; the mysterious Quake compromised the Slipgate by connecting it with its own teleportation system, using it to send death squads to the "Human" dimension in order to test the martial capabilities of humanity. 
The sole surviving protagonist in "Operation Counterstrike" is Ranger, who must advance, starting each of the four episodes from an overrun human military base, before fighting his way into other dimensions, reaching them via the Slipgate or their otherworld equivalent. After passing through the Slipgate, Ranger's main objective is to collect four magic runes from four dimensions of Quake; these are the key to stopping the enemy later discovered as Shub-Niggurath and ending the invasion of Earth.</desc>
		<image>./media/images/Quake.png</image>
		<video>./media/videos/Quake.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail>./media/boxart/Quake.png</thumbnail>
		<rating>0.8</rating>
		<releasedate>19960101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>id Software</developer>
		<publisher>id Software, Inc.</publisher>
		<genre>Shooter / 1st person-Shooter</genre>
		<genreid>259</genreid>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./SRB2.sh</path>
		<name>Sonic Robo Blast 2</name>
		<image>./media/images/SRB2.jpg</image>
		<video>./media/videos/SRB2.mp4</video>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Sonic Robo Blast 2 Kart.sh</path>
		<name>Sonic Robo Blast 2 Kart</name>
		<desc>Originally based on the Mario Kart mode of SRB2 Riders, it is a kart racing game with Sonic and SEGA-themed characters, items and maps. SRB2Kart features over 100 maps for two game modes: the main Race mode and a Battle mode where players fight each other using the items available in the game.</desc>
		<image>./media/images/srb2kart.png</image>
		<video>./media/videos/srb2kart.mp4</video>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Skijump3.sh</path>
		<name>Skijump3</name>
		<image>./media/images/skijump3.png</image>
		<video>./media/videos/skijump3.mp4</video>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Sonic 1.sh</path>
		<name>Sonic The Hedgehog</name>
		<desc>Sonic the Hedgehog is the first of many games starring Sega's premier rodent Sonic. It's a side scrolling platform game with a difference: speed. Sonic rushes through levels with incredible speed, allowing him to traverse loops and jumps with ease. The evil Dr. Robotnik has captured many of Sonic's animal friends and trapped them inside robots. Sonic can free his friends by destroying the robots with his spin attack. Meanwhile, Dr. Robotnik is trying to control the all-powerful chaos emeralds and Sonic must grab them before he does in the 3D rotating bonus levels. Sonic's weapon is his spin attack; while jumping, Sonic destroys hostile robots by touch. Throughout the platforming levels Sonic collects numerous rings. If Sonic is hit by an enemy, all the rings he's carrying fall out and scatter around; Sonic can quickly grab the rings back before they disappear. If Sonic is hit while not carrying any rings, he dies. Collecting 100 rings gives Sonic an extra life. There is also an invincibility bonus which temporarily protects Sonic from all attacks. The game is divided into several "zones", each of them containing three levels. At the end of each zone Sonic confronts Dr. Robotnik in a boss fight. Sonic the Hedgehog is a significant game because it gave Sega it's first real mascot, and established the Genesis as the video game system with "attitude."</desc>
		<image>./media/images/Sonic 1.png</image>
		<video>./media/videos/Sonic 1.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail>./media/boxart/Sonic 1.png</thumbnail>
		<rating>0.8</rating>
		<releasedate>19910623T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Sega</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<genre>Action-Platform</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./UQM.sh</path>
		<name>Star Control 2</name>
		<desc>Star Control II is a game based on exploration, space combat, diplomacy and resource gathering. Your main starship is the Precursor vessel and it can be used to travel between star systems; this uses up fuel. Raw materials are used as currency to make purchases in your space station headquarters; you can buy fuel, as well as improve your starship, buy smaller ships to accompany the starship as a fleet (to fight enemies), and hire crewmembers (who represent the ''health'' of your ships).
Raw materials are found on surfaces of planets and moons throughout the galaxy; you have to send a landing module to the planet and then guide it around the surface as it picks up the materials you found earlier with your scanner. Each planet is unique in the type of minerals and metals it is formed of. Some planets are plagued by natural dangers such as lightning storms, earthquakes or lava which can damage or destroy your landing modules. Non-sentient lifeforms can also be found and stunned to obtain biological samples. Special installations, objects and ruins can also be found on certain planets and explored.
Following the on-going war of the first Star Control game, the Alliance has lost. The Ur-Quan armada systematically hunts down the alliance races and imprisons them onto their homeworlds, including Earth. However unknown to the Ur-Quan, during the war, a small research vessel had been lost while sent to a distant star system looking for evidence of the ancient Precursor race. The survivors of this research team had come across the controls to a Starship factory and used it to build a Precursor supply vessel: one of the largest vessels in the galaxy. It's time for these Terrans to return to Earth...</desc>
		<image>./media/images/uqm.png</image>
		<video>./media/videos/uqm.mp4</video>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./SuperTux.sh</path>
		<name>Supertux</name>
		<image>./media/images/supertux.png</image>
		<video>./media/videos/supertux.mp4</video>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Undertale.sh</path>
		<name>Undertale</name>
		<image>./media/images/Undertale-image.png</image>
		<image>./media/images/undertale.png</image>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Sonic CD.sh</path>
		<name>Sonic the Hedgehog CD</name>
		<desc>This is a standard Sonic the Hedgehog side-scrolling action game. Dr. Robotnik has taken over the Little Planet, captured Amy, and created Metal Sonic with the goal of collecting all the Time Stones to be able to manipulate time and conquer the world.  It is up to Sonic to stop him, by rushing through levels set in different time periods, collecting Time Stones.
Sonic CD has features that take advantage of the CD format such as CD audio, video clips, and more levels (over 50 in total).</desc>
		<image>./media/images/Sonic CD.png</image>
		<video>./media/videos/Sonic CD.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail>./media/boxart/Sonic CD.png</thumbnail>
		<rating>0.8</rating>
		<releasedate>19931119T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Sonic Team</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Spelunky.sh</path>
		<name>Spelunky</name>
		<desc>Spelunky is a cave exploration / treasure-hunting game inspired by classic platform games and roguelikes, where the goal is to grab as much treasure from the cave as possible. Every time you play the cave's layout will be different. Use your wits, your reflexes, and the items available to you to survive and go ever deeper! Perhaps at the end you may find what you're looking for...</desc>
		<image>./media/images/spelunky.jpg</image>
		<video>./media/videos/spelunky.mp4</video>
		<rating>0.85</rating>
		<releasedate>19691231T190000</releasedate>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Tomb Raider 1.sh</path>
		<name>Tomb Raider</name>
		<desc>In Tomb Raider, you assume the role of a beautiful archaeologist, Lara Croft. She is a thrill seeker and is willing to do almost anything that puts her life in danger -- she enjoys it. Naturally, Lara jumped all over the opportunity to recover the powerful Scion, an ancient relic scattered throughout the caverns and temples of the world.
Played from a 3rd person 3D perspective, her adventure spans over 15 levels set in 4 distinct worlds and environments. As Lara, you'll have to solve ancient riddles in the Egyptian Pyramids, discover the Lost City of Atlantis and traverse through Ancient Rome all while looking for the artifact. Each level is laced with traps and hazards that require you to flip, swim and climb your way to safety and success.</desc>
		<image>./media/images/tr1.png</image>
		<video>./media/videos/tr1.mp4</video>
		<rating>0.7</rating>
		<developer>Core</developer>
		<publisher>Eidos</publisher>
		<genre>Platform / Adventure</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./VVVVVV.sh</path>
		<name>VVVVVV</name>
		<desc>It’s the game that’ll have you walking on the ceiling and looking up at the floor! VVVVVV is a challenging 2D action/platformer with one deceptively simple gameplay mechanic: Without the ability to jump, Captain Viridian must rely on inverting gravity to advance through hundreds of rooms and solve the puzzles he encounters therein.</desc>
		<image>./media/images/VVVVVV_-_The_Tomb_of_Mad_Carew.png</image>
		<video>./media/videos/VVVVVV_-_The_Tomb_of_Mad_Carew.mp4</video>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Space Cadet Pinball.sh</path>
		<name>Space Cadet Pinball</name>
		<image>./media/images/spacecadet.jpg</image>
		<video>./media/videos/spacecadet.mp4</video>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./AM2R.sh</path>
		<name>Another Metroid 2 Remake</name>
		<desc>AM2R (Another Metroid 2 Remake) is an action-adventure game and an unofficial remake of the 1991 Game Boy game Metroid II: Return of Samus in the style of Metroid: Zero Mission (2004).</desc>
		<image>./media/images/am2r.jpg</image>
		<video>./media/videos/am2r.mp4</video>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Super Mario War.sh</path>
		<name>Super Mario War</name>
		<image>./media/images/smw.png</image>
		<video>./media/videos/Super_Mario_War-video.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail>./media/boxart/smw-thumb.png</thumbnail>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./CorsixTH.sh</path>
		<name>Theme Hospital</name>
		<desc>Theme Hospital is a level-based hospital management simulation where players have to start on an empty building, and then assemble rooms with all kinds of material, from desks and file cabinets for the general diagnosis to the expensive ultra-scanners and x-rays to diagnose such bizarre diseases such as Bloaty Head, Slack Songue or Alien DNA, and treat them with with even more bizarre machines like an Head Inflator or a DNA fixer. There several additional rooms, such as a staff room for your employees to rest, a toilet so that patients don't have to relieve themselves in the corridors, a research department to get the most advanced diagnostic and treatment technologies and a training room where consultants can teach a thing or two to rookies, making them capable doctors. The size and layout of each room can be set by the player, according to the available space. In addition to rooms, the player must provide radiators, seating for patients and drink machines.
However, rooms don't run by themselves. Most diagnostic and clinics can work with regular doctors, but others like the operating theater and the research room require specialized staff while the ward, pharmacy and the fracture clinic require an attending nurse. At the same time, the hospital can't run without handymen cruising around the hospital to water up dry plants, clean up litter and vomit (after all, people go there because they are sick) and fix machines, while receptionists direct patients to the proper rooms.
As levels advance, the player faces increasingly harder situations: VIP visits, emergencies, epidemics and earthquakes, which can either take a toll on reputation or on the bank account. On the other hand, as more and more equipment is required, additional plots of land are available for purchase in later maps.</desc>
		<image>./media/images/Theme Hospital.png</image>
		<video>./media/videos/Theme Hospital.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail>./media/boxart/Theme Hospital.png</thumbnail>
		<releasedate />
		<developer>Bullfrog</developer>
		<publisher>Electronic Arts</publisher>
		<genre>Strategy</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Quake 3.sh</path>
		<name>Quake III</name>
		<desc>The third game in the Quake series is a departure from the previous games, focusing exclusively on multiplayer arena fighting with no story-driven singleplayer part - directly competing with Epic Games that did the same with the contemporary Unreal Tournament.
The offline part takes the player through a number of one-on-one and team-based challenges against AI-controlled opponents, slowly ranking upwards in difficulty, as the character of the player's choosing. Compared to the previous titles, the colours and general design of the game are much brighter and it shakes off the dominant shades of brown and grey the previous titles in the series were known for. The player's arsenal consists of new and familiar, but redesigned weapons, including a gauntlet (melee attacks) and a machine gun as the spawn weapons, a shotgun, plasma gun, lightning gun, rocket launcher, railgun and BFG. Each weapon has specific advantages, ranging from the amount of damage to reloading times and the ability to hit-scan opponents.</desc>
		<image>./media/images/quake3.png</image>
		<video>./media/videos/quake3.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail>./media/boxart/quake3.png</thumbnail>
		<rating>0.9</rating>
		<releasedate>19990930T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Activision</developer>
		<publisher>id Software</publisher>
		<genre>Shooter / 1st person-Shooter</genre>
	</game>
</gameList>
